Guide to the Russell Lee Collection
The Wittliff Collections
- Photographs of Russell and Jean Lee, 1904-1984
  - Soldiers in front of Pyramids, Cairo, Egypt. [On the left is Hiram Brailer and on the right is Russell Lee], 1943 (Box 11, Item WG043)
  - [Jean Lee], circa 1950 (Box 12, Item WG044)
  - [Jean Lee, cigarette in hand], undated (Box 12, Item WG044a)
  - [Jean Lee, outside], undated (Box 12, Item WG044b)
  - [Jean Lee, Portrait by Walter Barnes Studio], undated (Box 12, Item WG044c)
  - [Jean Lee], smoking cigarette], undated (Box 12, Item WG044d)
  - [Eugene Smith portrait] taken by unknown studio photographer (father of Jean Lee), undated (Box 12, Item WG044e)
  - [Shirley Smith] (mother of Jean Lee), undated (Box 12, Item WG044f)
  - [Russell Lee], circa 1955-1965 (Box 12, Item WG045)
  - [Russell Lee (sitting at a picnic table, scratching his head).], circa 1950-1960 (Box 12, Item WG046)
  - [Russell Lee (three quarter view, in dark suit, with his hands in his pockets)], circa 1955-1965 (Box 12, Item WG047)
  - [Russell Lee being interviewed by unidentified woman. One of his FSA photographs (entitled "White migrant mother with children, Weslaco, Texas, 1939) is behind him.], circa 1955-1965 (Box 12, Item WG048)
  - [Russell Lee (smiling)], circa 1955-1965 (Box 12, Item WG049)
  - [Russell Lee (profile)], circa 1955-1965 (Box 12, Item WG050)
  - [Russell Lee (three-quarter view)], circa 1955-1965 (Box 12, Item WG051)
  - [Russell Lee (amid plants and with camera in hand)], circa 1955-1965 (Box 12, Item WG052)
  - Russell Lee, Photographer; Austin, Texas, 1978 (Box 12, Item WG053)
  - [Russell Lee in his darkroom. His photograph "Hsintsin, China, 1944" rests in his lap] Austin, Texas, circa 1970-1980 (Box 12, Item WG054)
  - [Russell Lee, profile], circa 1970-1980 (Box 12, Item WG055)
  - [Russell Lee, profile], circa 1970-1980 (Box 12, Item WG055a)
  - [Russell Lee, frontal view], circa 1970-1980 (Box 12, Item WG056)
  - [Russell Lee, glasses in foreground], circa 1970-1980 (Box 12, Item WG057)
  - FSA Party - Barbara Morgan Studio. Barbara Morgan, Ed Rosskam, Russell Lee, 1976 (Box 12, Item WG058)
  - [Russell Lee speaking to unidentified man], circa 1970-1980 (Box 12, Item WG059)
  - [Russell Lee with unidentified man], undated (Box 12, Item WG059a)
  - [Russell Lee, wearing Hawaiian lei], circa 1970-1980 (Box 12, Item WG060)
  - [FSA Group portrait. Standing from left to right: Russell Lee, F. Jack Hurley, Arthur Rosthstein, Jack Delano. Marion Post Wolcott is seated in front], circa 1970-1980 (Box 12, Item WG061)
  - FSA Photographers [left to right: Russell Lee, Marion Post Wolcott, Arthur Rothstein, Jack Delano, John Collier], circa 1970-1980 (Box 12, Item WG062)
  - FSA Photographers [left to right: Russell Lee, Marion Post Wolcott, Arthur Rothstein, Jack Delano, John Collier] facing camera, circa 1970-1980 (Box 12, Item WG062a)
  - [Russell Lee], 1976 (Box 12, Item WG063)
  - [Russell Lee and unidentified man], 1976 (Box 12, Item WG064)
  - [Russell Lee, head and shoulders portrait], circa 1970-1980 (Box 12, Item WG065)
  - [Russell Lee, head and shoulders portrait, smiling], circa 1970-1980 (Box 12, Item WG066)
  - [Russell Lee, looking up], circa 1970-1980 (Box 12, Item WG067)
  - [Russell Lee, looking down], circa 1970-1980 (Box 12, Item WG068)
  - [Russell Lee, looking straight ahead], circa 1970-1980 (Box 12, Item WG069)
  - [Russell Lee, hand to chin], circa 1970-1980 (Box 12, Item WG070)
  - Russell Lee, in checkered jacket, looking off-camera], 1979 (Box 12, Item WG071)
  - [Portrait of Russell Lee], 1979 (Box 12, Item WG071a)
  - Russell Lee [on the porch of his home in Austin], 1980 (Box 12, Item WG072)
  - Russell Lee [on the porch of his home in Austin], 1980 (Box 12, Item WG073)
  - Russell Lee at Society for Photographic Education, National Conference, Philadelphia, 1983 (Box 12, Item WG074)
  - Russell Lee at home; Austin, Texas, 1983 (Box 12, Item WG075)
  - Russell Lee at home; Austin, Texas, 1983 (Box 12, Item WG076)
  - [Russell Lee, with two dogs, on his front lawn in Austin], 1984 (Box 12, Item WG077)
  - Jean and Russell Lee's dogs in window (Sally and Johnny Marlowe), 1984 (Box 12, Item WG077a)
- Photographs by Russell Lee, circa 1936-1961
  Arranged in chronological order by following Lee's career, this series consists of 352 photographs. Two-hundred forty-eight of these photographs by Russell Lee were taken for the Farm Security Administration (FSA) between 1936 and 1942. The gems of this part of the collection are the 130 vintage prints; most are complete with captions typed on the back by FSA staff. Making up the balance of the FSA group are 94 modern prints, 6 panels from the 1965 retrospective at the University of Texas, and 18 study prints.
  The balance of the photographs in the Collection provide the researcher with a comprehensive overview of Russell Lee's entire career, including his other government work: 16 photographs were taken during his commission during World War II with the Air Transport Command, and 37 photographs are from his tenure with the Coal Mines Administration.
  Russell Lee's post government work is also well-represented, including 33 photographs taken for a variety of publications after World War II in Texas where he photographed and spent most of his life. Other commercial work is also represented in his photographs of Italy for a photo essay in the Summer 1961 issue of Texas Quarterly(5 photographs), and his work for Standard Oil New Jersey/ARAMCO(6 photographs). The Collection also contains 8 photographs taken during the winter of 1935-1936, prior to Russell Lee joining the staff of the FSA, and one image of unidentified location or date.
  Titles with brackets were provided by the curator, titles without brackets indicate that they are the original title.
  - Pre-Farm Security Administration (FSA) Photographs, 1935-1936
    - Unemployed, New York City, Winter 1935-1936 (Box 13, Item WG078)
    - Unemployed, New York City, Winter 1935-1936 (Box 13, Item WG078a)
    - New York City, 1936 (Box 13, Item WG079)
    - Man with sign, New York City, Winter 1935-1936 (Box 13, Item WG080)
    - Unemployed, New York City, Winter 1935-1936 (Box 13, Item WG081)
    - [Snowy street scene, New York City], 1935-1936 (Box 13, Item WG082)
    - Auction, Woodstock, New York, 1936 (Box 13, Item WG083)
  - Farm Security Administration (FSA) Photographs, 1936-1942
    - Hands of Mrs. Andrew Ostermeyer, wife of a homesteader, Miller Township, Woodbury County, Iowa, 1936 (Box 13, Item WG085)
    - Hands of Mrs. Andrew Ostermeyer, wife of a homesteader, Miller Township, Woodbury County, Iowa, 1936 (Box 13, Item WG086)
    - Close up of Mr. and Mrs. Andrew Ostermeyer, homesteaders, Miller Township, Woodbury County, Iowa. They have lost their farm to a loan company, 1936 (Box 13, Item WG087)
    - Christmas dinner in home of Earl Pauley. Near Smithfield, Iowa. Dinner consisted of potatoes, cabbage and pie, 1936 (Box 13, Item WG088)
    - Mr. and Mrs. John Landers, tenant farmers, at the back door of their farmhouse, near Marseilles, Illinois, 1937 (Box 13, Item WG089)
    - Woman and child, flood refugees in schoolhouse, Sikeston, Missouri, 1937 (Box 13, Item WG090)
    - A flood refugee and his family in the schoolhouse at East Prairie, Missouri, 1937 (Box 13, Item WG092)
    - Two of the Bodray children in their home. Tipler, Wisconsin (vicinity), May 1937 (Box 13, Item WG094a)
    - Sprinkling wagon, Western Wisconsin City, Minnesota, 1937 (Box 13, Item WG095)
    - Mrs. H. Gerling and baby in living room in farmhouse near Wheelock, North Dakota, 1937 (Box 13, Item WG096)
    - Family of F. Peaches in their living room, farm near Williston, North Dakota, 1937 (Box 13, Item WG097)
    - Saturday night in a saloon, Craigville, (Koochiching) Minnesota, 1937 (Box 13, Item WG098)
    - Lumberjacks resting in bunk house at camp near Effie, Minnesota, 1937 (Box 13, Item WG100)
    - Loading logs onto rail road cars at camp near Effie, Minnesota, 1937 (Box 13, Item WG101)
    - Son of sharecropper sitting on front porch of shack home, New Madrid County, Missouri, 1938 (Box 13, Item WG102)
    - FSA client, Southeast Missouri Farms, New Madrid County, Missouri, 1938 (Box 13, Item WG103)
    - Child of a sharecropper, Southeast Missouri Farms, New Madrid County, Missouri, 1938 (Box 13, Item WG104)
    - Privy erection - fitting vent stack and lid on sanitary base. Southeast Missouri Farms, New Madrid County, Missouri, 1938 (Box 13, Item WG105)
    - Transient putting timetable into coat pocket. Note that label of coat reads New York. Sikeston, Missouri, 1938 (Box 13, Item WG106)
    - General view of auction, Sikeston, Missouri, 1938 (Box 13, Item WG107)
    - Wrestling match sponsored by American Legion, Sikeston, Missouri, 1938 (Box 13, Item WG107a)
    - Sons of fishermen, Olga, Louisiana, 1938 (Box 13, Item WG108)
    - Stevedores eating aboard El Rite, packet boat. Food supplied to crew consists almost entirely of carbohydrates with some cheaper cuts of meat. Sleeping quarters are not provided; stevedores sleeping in any available space. Pilottown, Louisiana, 1938 (Box 13, Item WG109)
    - Field house erection - close-up of partition framing. Southeast Missouri Farms Project, Missouri, 1938 (Box 13, Item WG110)
    - Blacksmith shop. Abbeville, Louisiana, 1938 (Box 13, Item WG111)
    - Blacksmith shop. Abbeville, Louisiana, 1938 (Box 13, Item WG112)
    - Children at the blackboard. Lake Dick Project, Arkansas, October 1938 (Box 13, Item WG112a)
    - Negro child residing in old trepagnier house near Norco, Louisiana, 1938 (Box 13, Item WG113)
    - Fortune teller, state fair, Donaldsonville, Louisiana, 1938 (Box 13, Item WG113a)
    - Negro crossing himself and praying over grave of relative in cemetery, All Saints' Day, New Roads, Louisiana, 1938 (Box 13, Item WG113b)
    - Family of migrant berry pickers, near Ponchatoula, Louisiana, 1938 (Box 13, Item WG114)
    - Negro migratory berry picker living in a corn crib near Hammond, Louisiana, 1938 (Box 13, Item WG115)
    - Child of white migrant worker ironing in camp near Harlingen, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG116)
    - Interior of tent home of white migrant family, near Harlingen, Texas. Bed on floor used by two boys, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG116a)
    - Spinach loading platform, La Pryor, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG117)
    - Farmers sitting on curb, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG118)
    - Oil field workers sanding on drill pipe with boilers and oil derrick in background, Kilgore, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG119)
    - Oil field workers talking, Kilgore, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG120)
    - Working on steam drilling engine, oil well, Kilgore, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG121)
    - Chuck and bedroll wagon of the tank gang on the highway. Near Marfa, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG122)
    - Man drinking malted milk at stand in street car terminal, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, July 1939 (Box 14, Item WG122a)
    - Cable tool equipment with operator. Oil well near Saint Louis, Oklahoma. This is equipment used in drilling, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG123)
    - Cable tool equipment with operator. Oil well near Saint Louis, Oklahoma. This is equipment used in drilling, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG124)
    - Cable tool equipment with operator. Oil well near Saint Louis, Oklahoma. This is equipment used in drilling, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG125)
    - Cable tool driller in Seminole Oil Field, Oklahoma, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG126)
    - Roustabouts during a lull in painting of derrick. Seminole Oil Field, Oklahoma, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG127)
    - Painting a derrick, Seminole Oil Field, Oklahoma. Notice lack of safety belts. Painters say that safety devices slow them down too much, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG128)
    - Traveling block and derrick against the sky, Seminole, Oklahoma, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG129)
    - Oil field worker, Seminole Oil Field, Oklahoma, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG130)
    - Adding a length of drilling pipe at oil well in Seminole Oil Field, Oklahoma. Clamps are put in place, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG131)
    - Adding a length of drilling pipe at oil well in Seminole Oil Field, Oklahoma. Lower end of traveling block is attached to pipe in rat hole by means of rope operated off winch, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG132)
    - Oil field driller, Seminole, Oklahoma, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG133)
    - Roustabout in the ditch digging crew. Notice the sweated shirt. Seminole Oil Field, Oklahoma, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG134)
    - Spanish-American woman testing temperature of earthen oven by determining length of time required to scorch wool, Taos County, New Mexico, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG135)
    - Hamburger stand with old brands, Dumas, Texas, September 1939 (Box 14, Item WG135a)
    - Mexican migrant boy drinking out of a water hose at a filling station where the truck which is taking him home from Mississippi where he has been picking cotton has stopped. Neches, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG136)
    - Mexican migrants drinking cold drinks and buying candy at filling station where the truck which is taking them to their homes in the Rio Grande Valley has stopped. They had been picking cotton in Mississippi. Neches, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG136a)
    - Negro worker at cotton compress taking a drink of water from bucket, Houston, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG136b)
    - Selling apples, Jacksonville, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG136c)
    - Home of Carrick Snodgrass before he obtained a Farm Security Administration tenant purchase loan. Floyd County, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG137)
    - Negro child playing phonograph in cabin home, Transylvania Project, Louisiana, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG138)
    - Negro mother teaching children numbers and alphabet in home of sharecropper, Transylvania, Louisiana, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG138a)
    - Threading cotton ropes into thread making machine, Laurel Cotton Mill, Laurel, Mississippi, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG139)
    - Tenant purchase clients at home. Hidalgo County, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG140)
    - Kitchen of tenant purchase client. Hidalgo County, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG140a)
    - White migrant mother with children, Weslaco, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG141)
    - White migrant mother with children, Weslaco, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG141a)
    - Son of white migrants sitting on trunk in tent home, Weslaco, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG142)
    - Mexican grave, Raymondville, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG143)
    - Daughter of migrant auto wrecker doing her lesson on bed in tenant home. Corpus Christi, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG144)
    - Soda jerker flipping ice cream into malted milk shakes, Corpus Christi, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG145)
    - Negro sitting on bench at side of barbecue stand made of galvanized metal, Corpus Christi, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG145a)
    - Soda jerker flipping ice cream into malted milk shakes, Corpus Christi, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG145b)
    - Mexican child in kitchen, San Antonio, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG147)
    - Camp of Mexican laborers working in and around El Indio, Texas. El Indio is a real estate development rural and urban, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG148)
    - Mexican grubbing out mesquite tree, El Indio, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG148a)
    - Cigar Stand. Gonzales, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG149a)
    - Kitchen of Mexican house, San Antonio, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG149b)
    - Mexican mother and child with impetigo. Crystal City, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG150)
    - Old man living alone in quarters furnished by the town. He also receives sustenance from town. He is an old-time trail driver. Crystal City, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG150a)
    - Breaking virgin soil by means of tractor-drawn plow. El Indio, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG151)
    - Young girl, pecan worker, classifying pecan meats, pecan shelling plants, San Antonio, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG152)
    - Separating the whole meats from the broken ones. Union plant, San Antonio, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG152a)
    - Mexican women pecan shellers at work. Union plant. San Antonio, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG152b)
    - Mexican lunch wagon serving tortillas and fried bean to workers in pecan shelling plant, San Antonio, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG152c)
    - Old farm couple in town on Saturday afternoon, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG153)
    - Farmer and daughter in wagon, Saturday afternoon, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG153a)
    - Farm family resting in grocery store on Saturday afternoon, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG154)
    - Druggist making up prescription, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG155)
    - Druggist in front of medicine shelf, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG156)
    - Street scene, Saturday afternoon, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG157)
    - County clerk, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG158)
    - Mass meeting called to discuss ways and means for raising county fund in order to continue WPA (Work Projects Administration) roadwork. San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG159a)
    - Mass meeting called to discuss ways and means for raising county fund in order to continue WPA (Work Projects Administration) roadwork. San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG159b)
    - Street scene, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG160)
    - Linotype operator, newspaper office, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG161)
    - Newspaper editor, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG162)
    - Choir in church, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG163)
    - Choir in church, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG164)
    - Music lesson in grade school, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG165)
    - Music lesson in grade school, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG165a)
    - Grade school children, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG166)
    - Entrance to San Augustine County Fair, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG166a)
    - Activity in front of the courthouse, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG167)
    - Activity in front of the courthouse, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG167a)
    - In the shoe repair shop, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG168)
    - Barber applying finishing touches to a shave, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG169)
    - Grade school superintendent, San Augustine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG170)
    - Farm Security Administration clients with team in front of barn. Sabine Farms, Marshall, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG171)
    - Cabin of Negroes living near Jefferson, Texas. This family owned about thirty acres buy were not farming it, doing day labor for a living, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG171a)
    - Street scene, Kilgore, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG172)
    - Street scene, Kilgore, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG173)
    - Street scene, Kilgore, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG174)
    - Railroad station and business section of Kilgore, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG175)
    - Oil derricks, Kilgore, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG176)
    - Oil well supply company, Kilgore, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG177)
    - Oil field worker, Kilgore, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG177a)
    - Oil Field worker, Kilgore, Texas, April 1939 (Box 14, Item WG177b)
    - A customer trying on a pair of boots in boot making shop. Alpine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG178)
    - Booth in hamburger stand, Alpine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG178a)
    - Leather which forms the heel is applied in layers and is filed down for accurate shaping. Boot shop, Alpine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG179)
    - Bootmaker lining up a pair of boots. Cowboy boot shop, Alpine, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG179a)
    - Saddle maker sewing in repairing saddle. Notice awl in his hand. Saddle shop, Alpine Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG179b)
    - Cowboy examining saddle. Ranch supply store, Alpine Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG179c)
    - Owner of the "Walking X" Ranch branding calf, near Marfa, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG180)
    - Camp cook at work with chuck wagon in background, cattle ranch near Marfa, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG181)
    - Camp round-up with corral on ranch near Marfa, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG182)
    - Homes of day laborers employed on large farm near Ralls, Texas. There are four thousand nine hundred acres in this farm. Nine tractors are used, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG183)
    - Day laborer filling planter hopper with kaffir corn seed, large farm near Ralls, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG183a)
    - Cook of SMS Ranch making bread in front of chuck wagon. Ranch near Spur, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG184)
    - Cowboys of the SMS Ranch serving themselves at dinner at chuck wagon. Ranch near Spur, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG185)
    - Cook of the SMS Ranch asleep after dinner. Ranch near Spur, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG186)
    - Interior of bunk house on Ranch near Spur, Texas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG187)
    - Statue to the watermelon, Weatherford, Texas, watermelon center, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG187a)
    - Migrant worker looking through back window of automobile near Prague, Oklahoma. Lincoln County, Oklahoma, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG188)
    - Farmer and wife near Warner, Oklahoma. This man has obtained a government loan (FSA) in Oklahoma. However, he migrated to Arizona two years ago and spent a good year and a half there doing day labor in the cotton and sugar beet fields. He still has one son in Arizona doing day laborer work. Another son returned home to his family saying he wanted to be with them all and all would fare alike; the close family feeling is evident in this class of people. This man's main complaint was of the poor condition of his house. He said that owners would do nothing to help the farmer; "Why if I want a piece of wire to fix a fence I have to steal it of course. I have not done exactly that yet, but if I knew where there was a piece handy I would.", 1939 (Box 14, Item WG189)
    - Son of a day laborer living in Arkansas river bottom at Webber Falls, Oklahoma, Muskogee County, Oklahoma, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG190)
    - Cutting a field of alfalfa with tractor-drawn equipment near Prague, Oklahoma, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG191)
    - Scene along the Arkansas river bottom at Webber Falls, Oklahoma, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG192)
    - Pouring water into radiator of migrant's car in the streets of Muskogee, where family has stopped [on the way] to Oklahoma, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG193)
    - The band at square dance in rural section of hills near McAllister, Oklahoma. Pittsburgh County. Sharecropper's home, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG194)
    - Dance where round and square dances are both performed at sharecropper home on Saturday night. Near McAllister, Oklahoma. Pittsburgh County, Oklahoma, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG195)
    - Migrant boy combing his hair at his home near Muskogee, Oklahoma, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG196)
    - Children sleeping during farewell party held for Oklahoma farm family who are setting out for California in the morning. Pittsburgh County, Oklahoma, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG197)
    - Detail of square-dance in hills near McAllister, Oklahoma. Pittsburgh County, sharecropper's home, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG198)
    - Children of May's Avenue Camp, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma. Their father is a trasher and they are playing with some of the things he picked up, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG199)
    - Food on table in community camp, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG200)
    - Part of Main Street, Forgan, Oklahoma, an agricultural ghost town, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG201)
    - Barbed wire and barbed wire fence covered by drifting sand, with tumbleweed growing up all around. This is in a section which one day is reputed to reproduce bushels of wheat to the acre near Syracuse, Kansas, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG202)
    - Scene in the sage brush county, south of Costilla, Taos County, New Mexico, 1939 (Box 14, Item WG203)